[MUSIC]
[음악]
Our next step is to evaluate
다음 단계는
the sentiment model that we've built.
감성 모델 평가하기입니다
Now, we just talked in this module about classification error,
이 모듈에서 분류 오류를 알아봤는데
precision, sorry, false positives and false negatives.
거짓 긍정과 거짓 부정이죠
And we're gonna explore that idea right here
이 개념을 자세히
in this demonstration in this notebook.
노트북에서 다뤄봅시다
So the sentiment model has a function called Evaluate.
감성 모델에는 평가 함수가 있습니다
And that function Evaluate allows you to evaluate its quality on some test data.
테스트 데이터에 대한 모델의 품질을 평가할 수 있게 도와주죠
And we're gonna provide a particular metric and
일종의 기준을 제공하는데
this metric is called the roc_curve.
roc_curve라는 겁니다
And we're gonna learn a little bit more about the roc_curve next.
roc_curve에 대해선 나중에 배우게 됩니다
But the roc_curve is a way to explore the false positives and
지금은 거짓 긍정과 거짓 부정을
false negatives in that confusion matrix that we discussed.
혼동 행렬에서 다루는 기법이라고 이해하면 됩니다
Now, here is, it shows you the results of evaluations that are hard to see in text.
평가 결과가 나왔는데 텍스트로는 알아보기 힘들죠
So let's do a little visualization of it, again, using Canvas.
Canvas로 시각화를 해봅니다
So we can use sentiment_model.show, and
sentiment_model.show를 입력하고
we're gonna show the view that we're gonna use,
뷰로는
is going to be the Evaluation view.
평가 뷰를 고릅니다
And here we go.
됐지요
Okay, this is really cool.
멋지군요
We've built a few things.
이것저것 나오는군요
So this is a precision recall, I'm sorry, this is what is called an roc_curve,
roc_curve라고 불리는 것입니다
it's a curve that trades off false positives with true positives.
거짓 긍정과 참 긍정의 균형을 나타내는 곡선이죠
Let me explain that a little bit.
잠시 설명하겠습니다
But first, let's look at these numbers over here.
먼저 숫자 세 개를 보시죠
So this is the confusion matrix.
혼동 행렬입니다
The number of true positives,
참 긍정의 수
the things that we got right that were true, is 26,455.
긍정 중 제대로 맞춘 숫자인데 26455개네요
So right here.
이겁니다
The number of true negatives was only 4,000, so 3,965.
참 부정은 4000개뿐입니다 정확히는 3965
So this is a highly unbalanced case.
매우 불균형한 사례군요
And then, the number of false positives and
거짓 긍정과 거짓 부정은
the number of false negatives is about the same.
거의 같습니다
The overall accuracy was 91.1%, so 0.911.
전체 정확도는 91.1%, 0.911
And also discuss a few metrics like precision recall and false count
정밀도와 재현율, 거짓 총계 등
which we're gonna learn more about later in the course and later in specialization.
앞으로 배우게 될 기준에 대해서 알아봅시다
Now, the thing about the false positives and false negatives is that
거짓 긍정과 거짓 부정에서 유의할 점은
there's a very natural way to change the threshold of what we believe
부정적인 클래스에서 긍정적인 클래스로 이행하는
the transition from negative class to positive class should be.
역치를 변경하는 쉬운 방법이 있다는 것입니다
So this is what the threshold shows on the right, but
역치가 오른쪽에 보이는데
let me first show it on the curve here.
곡선에서 일단 보여드리죠
So, you can see it is possible for me to get, for
여기선 아주 높은 참 긍정 비율을
example, a very high true positive rate.
볼 수 있습니다
So .4, if I, sorry, a very low .4.
그러니 0.4, 죄송합니다 아주 낮은 0.4
If I dont' allow myself to get any false positives.
거짓 긍정을 제한한다면
So, if I'm very worried about false positives that can be very conservative,
거짓 긍정만 제외하는 보수적인 태도를 취하면
get no false positives.
거짓 긍정이 없어집니다
But again not capture many of the true positives and make other mistakes.
그러나 참 긍정도 놓치고 다른 실수들이 생기죠
And you see.
그리고
As you go through the curve there's a kink here.
곡선을 따라가면 여기가 구부러졌는데
This is the point where you get not too many false positives but
그다지 많지 않은 거짓 긍정과
a lot of true positives.
많은 참 긍정이 공존하는 지점이죠
And then over on this end you get every true positive.
그다음 여기선 전부 참 긍정입니다
But you get a lot of false positives.
많은 거짓 긍정도 있지만요
How do you get every true positive but get less false positives?
모든 참 긍정과 적은 거짓 긍정을 맞출 수 있나요?
You just say every data point is positive.
모든 데이터 포인트를 긍정이라고 하면 됩니다
Then you get all the true positives, but you also make a lot of mistakes.
모든 참 긍정을 맞추지만 실수도 많이 나죠
And, we'll discuss more of this when we talk about precision recall curve.
정밀도/재현율 곡선를 다룰 때 자세히 알아보죠
But, nicely, we can change the threshold over here, and walk that curve up there.
편리하게도 역치를 바꿔서 곡선에서 왔다갔다 할 수 있지요
As you can see, and so for example, the far end, on the right,
오른쪽 끝에서는
you see that the true positive rate is really high.
참 긍정 비율이 정말 높습니다
There's no false positives, but that there's no true negatives.
거짓 긍정이 없지만 참 부정도 없습니다
So there's no false negatives, no true negatives, you just got everything right.
거짓 부정이 없고 참 부정도 없으니 다 맞췄습니다
And then you can slide it just the other way.
반대쪽으로 옮겨보죠
So you can play with this and
이리저리 움직여가며
really kind of get a good sense of what this curve really means, the roc_curve.
roc_curve가 어떤 의미를 가지는지 알아볼 수 있습니다
And that's the evaluation that we're gonna be doing.
우리가 할 평가도 이렇습니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]